Some of the greatest battles are fought with the heart.
Lady Jane is a drama, romance, history film directed by Trevor Nunn.
The death of King Henry VIII throws his kingdom into
chaos because of succession disputes.
His weak son, Edward, is on his deathbed.
Anxious to keep England true to the Reformation, a scheming minister John Dudley marries off his
son, Guildford to Lady Jane Grey, whom he places on the throne after Edward dies.
At first hostile to each other, Guildford and Jane fall in love, but they cannot
withstand the course of power which will lead to their ultimate downfall.
Lady Jane Grey, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Guilford Dudley, played by Cary Elwes.
John Dudley, Duke of Nothumberland, played by John Wood.
Henry Grey, Duke of Suffolk, played by Patrick Stewart.
Sir John Bridges, played by Joss Ackland.
Dr. Feckenham, played by Michael Hordern.
Lady Jane is a 1986 British costume-historical drama romance film, directed by Trevor Nunn,
written by David Edgar, and starring Helena Bonham Carter as the title character.
It tells the story of Lady Jane Grey, her marriage to Lord Guildford Dudley, and her
reign as the "Nine Days' Queen" following the death of Edward VI of England.
The story had previously been turned into a 1936 film, Tudor Rose, and a
1923 silent film, Lady Jane Grey; Or, The Court of Intrigue.
The film explores themes of tudor, tuberculosis, 16th century, british monarchy.
The tone is emotional.